<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:title>The province of New Jersey, divided into east and west, commonly called the Jerseys</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Faden, William, 1749-1836</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:contributor>Ratzer, Bernard</dcterms:contributor>
   <dcterms:contributor>Bancker, Gerard, 1740-1799</dcterms:contributor>
   <dcterms:created>1777</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>Bernard Ratzer, a Lieutenant in the Royal Artillery, prepared a survey of New Jersey in 1769 to assist the Boundary Commission in settling a long standing boundary dispute between the states of New York and New Jersey. London mapmaker William Faden published Ratzer's survey as a finished map in 1777 in his North American Atlas. Published during the American Revolution, the map depicts the area known to George Washington before the Battle of Monmouth, and shows the fortification at Valley Forge. Despite having several errors of location, the map is finely executed, and contains an elaborate cartouche of a farmhouse with landscape in the upper left corner. Displayed here is the first English edition of the map. A French derivative of this map by Georges-Louis LeRouge may be viewed online at: http://maps.bpl.org/id/rb15252.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:subject>New Jersey--Maps--Early works to 1800</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>New Jersey--Administrative and political divisions--Maps--Early works to 1800</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:medium>Maps</dcterms:medium>
   <dcterms:type>Image</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>06_01_008244</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:rights>https://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NKC/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>Richard H. Brown Revolutionary War Map Collection</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://cdm16829.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16829coll42/id/78</edm:isShownAt>
   <edm:preview>http://server16829.contentdm.oclc.org/cgi-bin/thumbnail.exe?CISOROOT=/p16829coll42&amp;CISOPTR=78</edm:preview>
   <dcterms:provenance>George Washington's Mount Vernon</dcterms:provenance>
</mdRecord>
