<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:title>Letter, Eleanor Parke Custis Lewis to Elizabeth Bordley Gibson, No. 78 Walnut Street Philadelphia, 1832 March 19</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Lewis, Eleanor Parke Custis, 1779-1852</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:contributor>Gibson, Elizabeth Bordley, 1777-1863</dcterms:contributor>
   <dcterms:created>1832-03-19</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>Mrs. [Thomas] Turner's requirements for a governess -- she has large family -- roads, bad weather and Mr. Lewis's illness have confined them at [Woodlawn] all winter -- unable as yet to see Mrs. G.'s niece, Miss B[ordley] -- gratified with account of Centennial celebration [of George Washington's birth] in Philadelphia -- "Philadelphia has never been backward in showing honor to his memory, altho they have not built a monument yet -- I am ashamed of Virginia, she is to pompous, too parading, too full of words rather than deeds -- she demands that the "remains" should not be removed from the State, and denies anything like a shelter or security for them -- They have tried to induce insurrection by their stupid inflamatory speech only made for effect to the north and [East ?]and deny anything to advance colonization and the real interests of those dark torments of our lives" -- "I was not one of the Petitioners, my dear Elizabeth, &amp; do not approve of Acts which sound loudly, but only increase the evils which menace us -- to do good, we must proceed cautiously and noiselessly - emancipation must be gradual - all this uproar creates discontent, and induces insurrection and murder[.] These ideals, T.J. Randolph, and Faulkner, and some others actually invite murder and outrage by telling these ignorant people that we fear them and are at their mercy - The "Liberator" has done less harm, than the speeches of our delegates" -- "The coach you mention was Govr. Penn's, and presented by the state to Grandmama - It was left in Phia and I do not recollect what became of it" -- Parke has two children, daughter born Feb. 7 [Eleanor Angela Isabella] both alike, and like EPL and their father [Edward Butler]. Name on original manuscript appears as "E. P. L.". Autograph letter initial signed, 4 pages, docketed "March 1831, Recd. March 21-1832", black seal with swan guarding nest &amp; motto "Amour maternel," postmarked Alexa Ca. Mar. 20.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
   <dcterms:type>Text</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>DA_003097</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>Elizabeth Bordley Gibson Collection</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://cdm16829.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16829coll15/id/587</edm:isShownAt>
   <edm:preview>http://server16829.contentdm.oclc.org/cgi-bin/thumbnail.exe?CISOROOT=/p16829coll15&amp;CISOPTR=587</edm:preview>
   <dcterms:provenance>George Washington's Mount Vernon</dcterms:provenance>
</mdRecord>
