<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:title>Letter, Jane Charlotte Blackburn Washington to George Corbin Washington, 1840 May 25 </dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Washington, Jane Charlotte Blackburn, 1786-1855</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:contributor>Washington, George Corbin, 1789-1854</dcterms:contributor>
   <dcterms:created>1840-05-25</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>Mount Vernon to Georgetown. Death of Aunt Blackburn detained her at Blakeley--engaged in having the remains of "our rever'd Uncle and Aunt [Bushrod and Anne Blackburn W-n] my beloved Husband [John A.] and dear Sister Mary Herbert inter'd in the Vault."--shocked at bad condition of some of coffins in vault--Cousin Lorenzo Lewis "had his ... Father laid in a grave immediately within the door-Crosswise"--details of grave she planned--West Ford prepared a coffin for G.C.W.'s nearest relatives--also had one made for Mr. Herbert and children but not room for them--only for one more and she wishes to be buried at feet of husband, uncle, aunt and sister--does not desire favors from government--"we are unwilling to sell our inheritance ... yet as the Nation already shares it with us, sense of justice points out necessity of an appropriation ... to enable us to keep up the improvements and meet the expences we are daily subjected to by the publick."--"endless intrusions and sacrifice of every thing like private right and domestic privacy ... arises frequently from a sincere ... desire of honouring the memory of Genl. Washington; 'Tis a feeling calculated to inspire and strenghthen virtuous and patriotic principles, and cement more firmly the ties that bind us together as a Nation. We have done, and shall continue to do all we can to keep the place from intire decay - it is yearly becoming more expensive and difficulty to do so; the buildings all ought to be thoroughly repaired, or they must in a few years go down - when that occurs-if unable to do better, I trust the family will erect a "Log Cabin," and still let the place descend to the name and family of Washington ..."--son [John] Augustine in Jefferson--her daughter and niece Mrs. Thos. Washington. Autograph letter signed, 3 pages, integral cover, black seal (blurred), docketed by G.C.W., postmarked "Alexandria May [?]."  </dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:subject>Mount Vernon (Va. : Estate)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Washington, George, 1732-1799 -- Tomb</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
   <dcterms:medium>Manuscript</dcterms:medium>
   <dcterms:type>Text</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>DA_004409</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>Historic Manuscript Collection </dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://cdm16829.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16829coll22/id/2391</edm:isShownAt>
   <edm:preview>http://server16829.contentdm.oclc.org/cgi-bin/thumbnail.exe?CISOROOT=/p16829coll22&amp;CISOPTR=2391</edm:preview>
   <dcterms:provenance>George Washington's Mount Vernon</dcterms:provenance>
</mdRecord>
