<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:title>Letter, Jane C. Washington to John A. Washington III, 1853 July 8</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Washington, Jane Charlotte Blackburn, 1786-1855</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:created>1853-07-08</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>Letter from Jane C. Washington, written from Blakeley, to her son that she learned of the conditional sale of Mount Vernon to a company from the newspapers. She expresses her hope that, if the estate cannot stay in the family, that it may become "the honored &amp; cherished property of the United States Government." At the end of the letter, Jane adds that she is "Earnestly praying my beloved son that you may in all things &amp; at all times, be guided by Divine Wisdom." Jane and her son Richard plan to visit John Augustine in a few days. They will take the Canal Boat at Harpers Ferry to Georgetown, and then proceed to Alexandria where they will spend the night. She looks forward to enjoying the scenery along the Potomac. Jane also mentions that Washington Irving is still at John Pendleton Kennedy's place and relates news some of Irving's travels. Irving had visited Mount Vernon in early 1853. Jane was pleased to see Irving join in her church's communion service last Sunday. Autograph letter signed, 2 pages.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
   <dcterms:type>Text</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>DA_000418</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NKC/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>Historic Manuscript Collection</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://cdm16829.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16829coll22/id/4335</edm:isShownAt>
   <edm:preview>http://server16829.contentdm.oclc.org/cgi-bin/thumbnail.exe?CISOROOT=/p16829coll22&amp;CISOPTR=4335</edm:preview>
   <dcterms:provenance>George Washington's Mount Vernon</dcterms:provenance>
</mdRecord>
