<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:title>Letter, George Washington to Marquis de Lafayette, 1798 October 8</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Washington, George, 1732-1799</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:contributor>Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert Du Motier, marquis de, 1757-1834</dcterms:contributor>
   <dcterms:created>1798-10-08</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>Washington sends this letter to Lafayette by his son -- he expresses sympathy for Lafayette's sufferings, and joy at hearing of his release from prison -- he explains why George Washington Lafayette did not come to live with him immediately on his arrival in America, the "delicate and responsible situation in which I stood as a public officer" -- young Lafayette's conduct has been exemplary -- filial affection made him impatient to return to France as soon as he heard of his father's release -- Mr. Felix Frestel has been like a father to the boy -- Lafayette has never stood higher in the affection of the people of America -- Washington writes "I have once more retreated to the shades of my own Vine and Fig tree, where I shall remain with best vows for the prosperity of that country for whose happiness I have toiled many years , to establish its Independence Constitution and Laws and for the good of mankind in general, until the days of my sojournment, which cannot be many, are accomplished."  -- young George will tell Lafayette of affairs in America and politics. Autograph letter not signed (last page missing), [From the content of this letter Fitzpatrick has concluded that it is misdated 1798; young Lafayette returned to France in the fall of 1797; he has used the Letter Book Copy to fill in the missing page and addressee.] A note by W.K. Bixby in dated 11.10.27 reads "Four pages Geo Washingtons writing Ladies Mt Vernon Society Compliments of W.K. Bixby," laminated, watermark (1794).</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
   <dcterms:type>Text</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>DA_001049</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NKC/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>George Washington Collection</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://cdm16829.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16829coll27/id/591</edm:isShownAt>
   <edm:preview>http://server16829.contentdm.oclc.org/cgi-bin/thumbnail.exe?CISOROOT=/p16829coll27&amp;CISOPTR=591</edm:preview>
   <dcterms:provenance>George Washington's Mount Vernon</dcterms:provenance>
</mdRecord>
