<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:title>Letter: John Augustine Washington III, Alexandria, to Jane C. Washington, Blakeley, 1837 November 23</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Washington, John Augustine, 1821-1861</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:contributor>Washington, Jane Charlotte Blackburn, 1786-1855</dcterms:contributor>
   <dcterms:created>1837-11-23</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>Letter written by a sixteen-year-old John Augustine Washington III in Alexandria, Virginia to his mother Jane C. Washington at Blakeley plantation near Charlestown, West Virginia. The address on the back page of the letter notes that the letter was delivered by Jim Mitchell ("Jim Mitchum") with a note from John Augustine that says "I let Jim have $1.00 for his expenses." Jim Mitchell, who was later employed by the Mount Vernon Ladies Association, was enslaved by the Washington family at the time. John Augustine tells his mother "Mr. Skidmore finished his work at Mount Vernon yesterday, but I have not seen him yet so that I cant say what has been done" and also notes "On Saturday I went to Georgetown, Cousin and his family were not at home so that I could not get the pictures." He reports that West Ford has taken the cloth that arrived for Jane from Dumfries down to Mount Vernon and discusses butter sales, corn production, hogs, and resuming his studies. He also asks Jane if the servants are "conducting themselves well" and is worried they will give her "a good deal of trouble coming in with their complaints." Autograph letter signed, partial seal, 2 pages. </dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:medium>Manuscript</dcterms:medium>
   <dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
   <dcterms:type>Text</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>DA_000420</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>John Augustine Washington III and Descendants Papers</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://cdm16829.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16829coll25/id/644</edm:isShownAt>
   <edm:preview>http://server16829.contentdm.oclc.org/cgi-bin/thumbnail.exe?CISOROOT=/p16829coll25&amp;CISOPTR=644</edm:preview>
   <dcterms:provenance>George Washington's Mount Vernon</dcterms:provenance>
</mdRecord>
