<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:title>Letter, George Washington to Robert Lewis, 1799 August 17</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Washington, George, 1732-1799</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:contributor>Lewis, Robert, 1769-1829</dcterms:contributor>
   <dcterms:created>1799-08-17</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>Washington writes that Lewis failed to endorse Ariss's note for rent -- Washington will give Kercheval extra time to pay if he has really been unfortunate in crops, not that he can easily afford it -- Mount Vernon has "more working negroes by a full moiety than can be employed in the farming system"  -- sale of his lands barely keeps him afloat -- "to sell the over-plus [of negroes] I cannot because I am principled against this kind of traffic in the human species. - To hire them out, is almost as bad, because they could not be disposed of in families to any advantage, and to disperse the families I have an aversion." -- he is determined to settle plantations on some of his western lands, but knows most of it is leased with encumbrances -- questions Lewis as to value, availability, etc. of his western lands for this purpose -- drought has ruined oats and possibly corn at Mt. Vernon -- poor grass compels him to sell some of asses, so he asks whether there is any market for them in Fauquier? -- Washington is glad that Lawrence Lewis has recovered some of his health -- the postscript relates that he sends the letter under cover to Mr. Bush at Winchester or at Fauquier Courthouse. Autograph letter signed, 4 pages [AR, 1954 lists a cover with this, but seems to be missing now], silked. Name on original manuscript appears as "G. Washington".</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:subject>Mount Vernon (Va. : Estate)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Slavery</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
   <dcterms:type>Text</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>DA_000879</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NKC/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>George Washington Collection</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://cdm16829.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16829coll27/id/653</edm:isShownAt>
   <edm:preview>http://server16829.contentdm.oclc.org/cgi-bin/thumbnail.exe?CISOROOT=/p16829coll27&amp;CISOPTR=653</edm:preview>
   <dcterms:provenance>George Washington's Mount Vernon</dcterms:provenance>
</mdRecord>
