<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mdRecord xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:title>Letter, George Washington to Burwell Bassett Esqr.,1775 June 19</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Washington, George, 1732-1799</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:contributor>Bassett, Burwell, 1764-1841</dcterms:contributor>
   <dcterms:created>1775-06-19</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>Washington writes to his brother-in-law from Philadelphia, "I am now Imbarked on a tempestuous Ocean, from whence perhaps, no friendly harbour is to be found. I have been called upon by the unanimous voice of the Colonies to the Command of the Continental Army. It is an honour by no means aspired to. It is an honour I wished to avoid, as well from an unwillingness to quit the peaceful enjoyment of my Family, as from a thorough conviction of my own Incapacity and want of experience in the conduct of so momentous a concern ... I can answer but for three things, a firm belief of the justice of our Cause, close attention in the prosecution of it, and the strictest Integrity" -- fears for the cause and for his character if he fails -- Congress in Committee have consented to a Continental Currency and have ordered 2 million dollars to be struck off for payment of troops and other expenses of defense -- 15,000 men voted as a Continental army, and he hopes more will be voted -- other high officers not named yet -- asks him and Mrs. Bassett to visit Mt. Vernon and take Mrs. Washington down to [Eltham] with them -- uneasy at leaving her alone at Mount Vernon. Autograph letter signed, part of a separate cover, franked by George Washington, laminated, watermarked (LVG surmounted by crown and powder horn, &amp; IV). Name on original manuscript appears as "G. Washington". Autograph letter signed, 3 pages and partial cover.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:subject>United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
   <dcterms:type>Text</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>DI-0098</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NKC/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>George Washington Collection</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://cdm16829.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16829coll27/id/15</edm:isShownAt>
   <edm:preview>http://server16829.contentdm.oclc.org/cgi-bin/thumbnail.exe?CISOROOT=/p16829coll27&amp;CISOPTR=15</edm:preview>
   <dcterms:provenance>George Washington's Mount Vernon</dcterms:provenance>
</mdRecord>
